MD Rakibul Alom

Full-Stack Developer

CAREER OBJECTIVE

Having 2 years of experience in developing user Interface and professional web applications and seeking an opportunity to extend my web development career. Having a positive outlook and always willing to learn new traits. I work well both independently and as part of a team.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Junior Software Developer

October 2020 - March 2021

United IT Solutions Limited, Dhaka

Responsibilities:

- · Working as a PHP Laravel developer.
- · Create a demo project for the client.
- Train the client after the project was completed.

Search Engine Optimization Specialist

April 2022 - Present

Nitro9. Remote

Responsibilities:

- · All website case studies.
- SEO audits, tools & plugins, performance, meta-data info.
- · Search engine performance, local-SEO, and pre-lunch audit.

PROJECTS

Car Dealer Zone: Buy & Sell

November 2022

 $eCommerce \cdot Live \ Site \cdot Client \ Repo \cdot Server \ Repo$

- Car Resell Service & Dashboard management.
- · Payment method system with Stripe Integrated.
- Authentication, Blog, About, 404 Page, SEO-friendly coding.

 $\textbf{Technology:} \ \textbf{HTML} \cdot \textbf{CSS} \cdot \textbf{Tailwind} \cdot \textbf{React} \cdot \textbf{Firebase} \cdot \textbf{ExpressJS} \cdot \textbf{MongoDB}$

StorialTech - Blog of News and Technology

January 2020

Blog/News · Live Site · GitHub

- User-Friendly Admin control panel with Authorization.
- SEO-friendly and W3Validate coding interface.
- Users can register, log in, and like-comment on posts.

Technology: HTML \cdot CSS \cdot Boostrap \cdot Laravel \cdot MySQL

DoctorEbari: Get Doctor Appointment

October 2020

Services · Live Site · GitHub

- · Doctor appointment, details & services system.
- · Doctors, hospital, diagnostic, ambulance, blog, shop, contact page.
- SEO-friendly coding, user-friendly admin panel, and SMS service.

 $\textbf{Technology:} \ \mathsf{HTML} \cdot \mathsf{CSS} \cdot \mathsf{Boostrap} \cdot \mathsf{Laravel} \cdot \mathsf{MySQL}$

Sylhet, Bangladesh +880 1571-334142 rakibalom94@gmail.com LinkedIn || GitHub

SKILLS

Frontend

Html, CSS, Bootstrap, Tailwindcss, JavaScript, ReactJs

Backend

Express, Nodejs, MongoDB, MVC, Firebase, PHP, Laravel, MySQL

Tools

VS Code, Git, GitHub, cPanel, Xampp

EDUCATION

Diploma-in-Engineering

2020

Sylhet Technical School & College, BD Computer Technology, CGPA (3.60)

COURSES

Complete Web Development Course With Jhankar Mahbub

Programming Hero, Online June 2022 – Present

Advance Web Development

Binary Technical Institute, Sylhet February 2020 – April 2020

Web Design & Development

LEDP, Online

June 2020 - September 2020

Languages

- · Bengali [Native]
- · English [Fluent]
- · Hindi [Conversational]